<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-21T08:22:05-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">archives</title><subtitle>thoughts (for my) posterity, could be absolute garbage</subtitle><author><name>the archiver</name></author><entry><title type="html">This is only a Roof</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/20/this-is-only-a-roof.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This is only a Roof" /><published>2022-09-20T23:45:13-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-20T23:45:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/20/this-is-only-a%20roof</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/20/this-is-only-a-roof.html"><![CDATA[<p>
    It was paradise. Everything was great; no rules, no requirements, nothing. Well, almost
    nothing. Jack's mum usually would be around, meandering her house. I always wondered
    what she did but Jack would only scoff and said she was good for nothing. I would see 
    her on her desk, and in the most sincerest form, acting busy whilst doing nothing. But I
    was young and carefree, and all I thought was "this is definitely better than my place".
</p>

<p>
    Jack's home to me was paradise, if paradise exists. He would corroborate that we were 
    heading to his place to his study and ended up doing nothing of such. If I could name
    a best friend in my teenage year, it would be him. Plus, we were doing fairly well in 
    school and our parents stopped questioning what we did or did not do, not that Jack's mum
    cared nor his dad, who I've only seen once, ransacking the kitchen hurriedly left. At 
    least he left some food that he cooked, and Jack said we could eat it and so we did.
</p>

<p>
    Of course, the background image was a little misleading, well actually, very much so. A
    typical flat that you would find in Penang would look more like the ones below; one that 
    reflects a lot of the spirit of the people. Some would call it decrepit but I beg to defer.
    To me, this was liberty. Something that I could never obtain in my suburban home with 
    at least 5 times the size a tiny flat where Jack used to live. But the space that it 
    gave me did not translate to freedom, because in my home, there are rules.
</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="/blog/img/flats_penang.jpg" alt="Demo Image">

<p>
    "This is only a roof." blurted Jack as we were in a random conversation that I could not 
    remember. "What do you mean?" I replied, confused. "I have lived here on this island for
    about 15 years but I never have a place that I could call home." "This is rented, it is not
    mine. Who knows when I have to move?" with his voice increasingly emotional. I stayed quiet.
    I knew that this was not a conversation that I want to have, nor did I understand what he 
    was saying. I always thought that I would trade places with him in a heartbeat if I had
    the chance to, and his complaints were merely a relic of his misunderstandings with
    his parents.
</p>

<p>
    Now that I am in search for a home, I have begun to wrap my head
    around what he felt. I don't think 
    that there is truly a way to understand since it is my choice to move. I have a house in 
    Malaysia where my parents would welcome me back without a doubt. After all, an empty
    birdnest can be at times hollowing. 
</p>

<p>
    And in all honesty, this realization has slowly crept into me. It was cruel that a 15 year
    old should feel that way as I realize that to this day, I lack the maturity to comprehend
    nor grasp the idea of homelessness with home. The feeling that my country has rejected me,
    denies my existence hovers between my conscious and unconscious, sometimes banishing me
    to a solemn torment that I do not belong. Full stop.
</p>

<p>
    Maybe our definitiion of belonging, of a home, is wrong. Maybe it should evolve over time.
    But the undeniable fact is that feeling belonged is perhaps an innate feature that we have 
    unlearned from the past in this modern world.
</p>]]></content><author><name>the archiver</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was paradise. Everything was great; no rules, no requirements, nothing. Well, almost nothing. Jack's mum usually would be around, meandering her house. I always wondered what she did but Jack would only scoff and said she was good for nothing. I would see her on her desk, and in the most sincerest form, acting busy whilst doing nothing. But I was young and carefree, and all I thought was "this is definitely better than my place".]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life as a Supporting Character</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/18/life-as-a-supporting-character.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life as a Supporting Character" /><published>2022-09-18T09:45:13-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-18T09:45:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/18/life-as-a-supporting-character</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/18/life-as-a-supporting-character.html"><![CDATA[<p>
    "You are the most useless gay friend ever!" sniggered Mariano as both of us stood 
    in the Railyard with beer in our hands. "Why don't you find a guy for me instead, be 
    useful for once." I retorted jokingly and he said "It does not work that way, haven't you 
    watched any tv shows before?"
</p>

<p>
    In the crowd of red, I couldn't really tell what was happening at all. Surrounded by
    the boisterous cheers because of an apparent touchdown and grunts from our opponents,
    Zayne told me that we were doing good and I trusted him. After all, I don't believe
    that I have even held a pigskin, if that is what it is called. All I could think then
    was that I paid $7 for less than a can of beer, and I am leaving behind work that I 
    know I would regret. But hey, it was game day and so, there we were. 
</p>

<p>
    Squinting my eyes, I still could not see anything. It wasn't bad eyesight that 
    plagued me, there was a guy infront of me that seemed to have a penchant to 
    block my view. Irritated, I turned to Mariano and told him that. He laughed and I 
    did too. There was nothing new to be the shortest guy around, I have gotten used to it.
    "Look at that girl with a cap behind you" Mariano signaled, nudging me subtly to her but 
    I turned around immediately which he responded kindly by hitting me on my shoulder.
</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="/blog/img/plastic_cup.jpg" alt="Demo Image">

<p>
It is not difficult to feel out of place being a 5'6'' gay Malaysian (Zayne would say 5'4'' instead) in a tailgate party.
The tinge of envy I felt for the blonde was palpable, which bothered me further. 
Why did I care the attention that she had, of which she didn't even know exists? It was 
a confusing time, though it should not have been. But within the moments I started to
understand what it felt like to be a supporting character. Maybe the world is too small
for all of us to be the main character, or even our main character. 
</p>

<p>
    There is a bitterness with that thought, but after all, I was just another guy in red 
    within a sea of red, what is less 'supporting' than that? I couldn't just leave behind 
    the fact that I was one of the same, but different at the same time. But does it even 
    matter? Perhaps all I have to start doing is being accustomed to the life of a supporting
    character. And it is okay.
</p>]]></content><author><name>the archiver</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA["You are the most useless gay friend ever!" sniggered Mariano as both of us stood in the Railyard with beer in our hands. "Why don't you find a guy for me instead, be useful for once." I retorted jokingly and he said "It does not work that way, haven't you watched any tv shows before?"]]></summary></entry></feed>