<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-10-23T09:48:38-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">archives</title><subtitle>thoughts for (my) posterity, could be absolute garbage</subtitle><author><name>jhojy</name></author><entry><title type="html">Of a different shade</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/10/22/fall.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Of a different shade" /><published>2022-10-22T23:45:13-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-22T23:45:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/10/22/fall</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/10/22/fall.html"><![CDATA[<p>
   As the leaves scurried, the wind carrasses me. <br>
    In the midst of the eddy, I am the only constancy. <br>
    As they leave, hurried, no one here to harrass me. <br>
    In the move from greenery, I am only here temporarily. <br>
</p>

<p>
    As we embrace a different color, the shades fell. <br>
    In light of this new phase, everything seems to falter. <br>
    As I embark in this new tour, only memories would dwell.<br>
    In the lavender haze, all is just a barter. 
</p>

<p>
    I will miss you, Lincoln.
</p>]]></content><author><name>jhojy</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[As the leaves scurried, the wind carrasses me. In the midst of the eddy, I am the only constancy. As they leave, hurried, no one here to harrass me. In the move from greenery, I am only here temporarily.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ambivalent Attachments</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/10/21/ambivalent-attachment.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ambivalent Attachments" /><published>2022-10-21T23:45:13-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-21T23:45:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/10/21/ambivalent-attachment</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/10/21/ambivalent-attachment.html"><![CDATA[<p>
   Enveloped, the surreal feeling of being a small part of a whole, covered in warmth
   that promises security. Without an explicit proclamation, there is always the subtle
   agreement that this was all between us. The beauty of it all was discovered in cruising
   through barren-roads; calming silence, random commotions, and pretending that there was
   something to say. Furtive glances (it was my modus operandi), as your profile has 
   that enigmatic tranquility as you maintain your focus at the road ahead. It was a haze.
</p>

<p>
    The intermissions between weekends, when it would take 20 minutes for a saving grace
    to arrive, which peppered my summer with hope amidst the gruelling work. Waiting at an 
    airport bar, then we took off, even only for a few hours, these momentary feelings
    made all of summer worth it. I should have told you that. I don't think you know how 
    much that meant to me.
</p>

<p>
    And my lurching concerns crept up, and they were realized in the most dishonorable fashion. As autumn
    came, the disguise of security fell; as easy it was to rip the envelope that we 
    pretend guaranteed some unfounded binding agreement. Now bare and open, I guess
    nothing will ever be the same. But I am glad when it could be, it was, despite being only
    fluttering moments, they made them more potent. No longer as a peripheral sensation, but 
    they were (they had to be!) a concerted effort to embrace every single second, knowing
    that the end might just be around the corner.
</p>

<img class="img-fluid img-thumbnail" src="/blog/img/mau.JPG" alt="Demo Image">

<p>
   Christmas in Mexico, that was the plan. Though it slowly devolved with you 
   smoking with your boys, as I was consumed by work. Maybe all along I was all on my own,
   though your company made it all bearable. Is there no way to confront the reality that 
   a huge part of you was gone when the car crashed. But I could never bring myself to 
   face that, nor did you. How did we just relegate our lives to the whims of chance?
   And as the ugly head reared, we were helpless to see ourselves through it.
</p>

<p>
    But look ahead, champ! The beauty and the flaws, the choices and the mistakes, and all
    that complement your life, make this whole and complete. And as I assiduosly pour
    through what could be, your life does not rest on my divinity. Your life is yours, and 
    your choices to put the pieces together, and put up a fight as you never shied away. 
    The envelope was perhaps a superfluous cover all along, and that should have always 
    been the case. And maybe the weekends would be the same, for the both of us, with
    different company, but the legacy lives on.
</p>]]></content><author><name>jhojy</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Enveloped, the surreal feeling of being a small part of a whole, covered in warmth that promises security. Without an explicit proclamation, there is always the subtle agreement that this was all between us. The beauty of it all was discovered in cruising through barren-roads; calming silence, random commotions, and pretending that there was something to say. Furtive glances (it was my modus operandi), as your profile has that enigmatic tranquility as you maintain your focus at the road ahead. It was a haze.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When the World Conspires for me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/10/03/When-the-world-conspires-for-me.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When the World Conspires for me" /><published>2022-10-03T23:45:13-05:00</published><updated>2022-10-03T23:45:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/10/03/When-the-world-conspires-for-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/10/03/When-the-world-conspires-for-me.html"><![CDATA[<p>
   The whirlwind that is life has never ending twists and turns. As I was preparing and checklisting
   all that I can plan, I left GRE to the stars and they were not in my favor. ETS
   would be damned for not allowing me to take the exam though in all honesty the only
   culpable was me. How could I have not checked the simple requirements, when Jack 
   was even surprised I never thought about that. 
</p>

<p>
    The anger, the ire and the shame dissipated quite quickly as I turned 23, realizing
    that this number seem to feel of less importance, where it no longer marks an important
    transition in life. How quickly it meant nothing after obtaining the highly coveted 
    horizontal driver's licence when you turn 21, and it seems that that was the only thing
    that mattered for a while. Until it was not. And with that, I found out how useless it 
    could be, as it was not 'sufficient' to be get me into my GRE test.
</p>

<p>
    Oh how much life has changed since I felt a sense of 'consciousness'! I do not know
    when did that happen, nor do I quite recall what happened in those years. Nor do
    I think that I could recall the time that I had grown some 'sensibility', as they 
    were peppered with angst and guilt; two elements that are essential for troubled
    childhood. But how much fortunes have changed, when it almost seemed like throwing $200
    out of the window left me barely fazed. 
</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="/blog/img/writing_background.jpg" alt="Demo Image">

<p>
   Is it too much to ask for a time machine? I profess I am not the most selfless person;
   I would never risk going to Germany to try to kill Hitler. Somehow people just assume 
   that it would be a walk in the park, not considering the nearly impossible task to 
   get a gun and perhaps even to get into Austria just to murder a baby in his crib. No, I 
   wouldn't do any of those, but I need to let my younger self know that the world 
   conspires for you. Your parents would not disown you. In fact, they love you more than 
   ever! Life is not a dead-end road, and that perhaps your goals today are merely a figment
   of a poorly thought out desire, that you soon realize could never bring you true 
   happiness. You are, at 23, alone and by all metrics a failure. But he is happier than he
   ever felt in his life!
</p>

<p>
    Fortunes change, and maybe reflecting on this a year later would not make any sense. In 
    retrospect, I am very fortuitous. For some reason, the worst outcomes turn their heads 
    around and present me a blessing that I never would realize until much later. I am grateful,
    I am happy, and I am contented. That is enough.
</p>]]></content><author><name>jhojy</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The whirlwind that is life has never ending twists and turns. As I was preparing and checklisting all that I can plan, I left GRE to the stars and they were not in my favor. ETS would be damned for not allowing me to take the exam though in all honesty the only culpable was me. How could I have not checked the simple requirements, when Jack was even surprised I never thought about that.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fuck grass, they are unnatural</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/24/fuck-grass-they-are-unnatural.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fuck grass, they are unnatural" /><published>2022-09-24T23:45:13-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-24T23:45:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/24/fuck-grass-they-are-unnatural</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/24/fuck-grass-they-are-unnatural.html"><![CDATA[<p>
   "You know, they shoot you in Texas if you walk on the grass." Jesse murmured, intimating
   that we should walk on the paved road as we were heading towards the Union. "Really? Well,
   not surprising, it is Texas after all." I replied, not bothered given the fact that I am
   safely in the warm heartland of the Midwest. "I was just kidding, but you'd get stares
   if you do that" Jesse said. 
</p>

<p>
    I never quite understood why she not so subtly suggested us to walk on the paved road. 
    It probably was just her white platform shoes that she wears all the time, compensating
    her lack of height. A little part of me does wish that platform shoes are more of a thing
    for men in general. But there is a sense of defiance while walking, a small win for my
    rebellious heart to fight against the tyrannical forces that shape this world! Though in
    all honesty, I would take the paved road if was the shorter of the two. It was a 
    testament of indolence, not insubordination.
</p>

<p>
    There's plenty to be liked on the paved road. One can simply saunder to the path that it
    leads, hoping that everything is the same. Never caring that if there would be mud to avoid,
    or roots to be tripped. Most of it, if well constructed and maintained, provides a rhythm of 
    steps that mimics the pace of life a normal person would desire. The grass at the side are 
    simply hints of the reality that we live in, a simulacra one might call, where the land
    lays fallow and the grass well trimmed. There is a sense of peace, while constant 
    fabrication was done to perpetuate this tranquility.
</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="/blog/img/jesse.jpeg" alt="Demo Image">

<p>
    What is the fuss then with all this hate on grass? Brent would argue that this is 
    an unnatural way of how people walk and the right to walk has been infringed too often
    without challenge. I'd agree with that. But it has been an endeavor in humanity's
    entirety to shape and polish out the impurities that life promises, eroding the 
    dirt to keep our white platformed shoes white. The ugly truth, exemplified by the 
    untame wilderness, has been extensively patched up by our eagerness to deny its existence. 
</p>

<p>
    The allure is comprehensible, and one should be justifiably contempt of those who
    deny it. I am no exception, constantly finding myself tapering over the cracks in life
    that bothers me. Though I find myself tearing down this tapestry to peek into what it
    has to offer. Counterintuitively, I find life unbearable with constancy, when I know that 
    my road is paved; but simultaneously fear what I do not know. And so now I am stepping
    on this well-mowed, well-maintained pasture, derived from the suburban hellscape that I 
    had once called home. And that is perhaps the road I will take, the determined
    stochastic life I will call my future, shrouded with known mysteries that I would one
    day discover.
</p>]]></content><author><name>jhojy</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA["You know, they shoot you in Texas if you walk on the grass." Jesse murmured, intimating that we should walk on the paved road as we were heading towards the Union. "Really? Well, not surprising, it is Texas after all." I replied, not bothered given the fact that I am safely in the warm heartland of the Midwest. "I was just kidding, but you'd get stares if you do that" Jesse said.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The puppetmasters around you</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/21/people-around-you.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The puppetmasters around you" /><published>2022-09-21T23:45:13-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-21T23:45:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/21/people-around-you</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/21/people-around-you.html"><![CDATA[<p>
    It is easy to be caught up by work, life and everything in between. This seems to be 
    all too relatable. The fact that I am in a college town and am a college student just
    enables me to simply turn a blind eye to the community around me. There is no point, as 
    the lack of wisdom goes, of the people around you but your peers. Plus, it helps that 
    they are young and pretty and humans have the penchant of sidelining everything that
    doesn't catch the eye.
</p>

<p>
    Though it might sound innocuous, from an economic point of view, my indifference
    was costly. The opportunities that I could have explored, the people that I would have
    otherwise known if I hadn't lived in a world filled only by the immediate gratifications
    of college life. I have never quite understood Brent's ruminations about 'community'; I have to admit that
    it is a preoccupation that I have never shared with him. But it took an obscure
    coffee shop that somehow illuminated the moving parts of the city. I am somehow in
    the group of people who is secretly running this city! 
</p>

<p>
    Puppetmasters are often painted as diabolical with the predisposition of abusing
    their power. Perhaps that is true, but we forget that the puller of string can be 
    one who does not control but brings us together instead.
    This is just a note to self, in all honesty. With time weathering memory, I just
    wanted to make sure that whatever reason the reader might be here for, 
    I hope he remembers that there are people around you, and puppetmasters too.
</p>]]></content><author><name>jhojy</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It is easy to be caught up by work, life and everything in between. This seems to be all too relatable. The fact that I am in a college town and am a college student just enables me to simply turn a blind eye to the community around me. There is no point, as the lack of wisdom goes, of the people around you but your peers. Plus, it helps that they are young and pretty and humans have the penchant of sidelining everything that doesn't catch the eye.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">This is only a Roof</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/20/this-is-only-a-roof.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="This is only a Roof" /><published>2022-09-20T23:45:13-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-20T23:45:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/20/this-is-only-a%20roof</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/20/this-is-only-a-roof.html"><![CDATA[<p>
    It was paradise. Everything was great; no rules, no requirements, nothing. Well, almost
    nothing. Jack's mum usually would be around, meandering around her house. I always wondered
    what she did but Jack would only scoff and said she was good for nothing. I would see 
    her on her desk, and in the most sincerest form, acting busy whilst doing nothing. But I
    was young and carefree, and all I thought was "this is definitely better than my place".
</p>

<p>
    Jack's home, to me, was paradise, if paradise existed. He would corroborate that we were 
    heading to his place to study and ended up doing nothing of such. If I could name
    a best friend in my teenage year, it would be him. Plus, we were doing fairly well in 
    school and our parents stopped questioning what we did or did not do, not that Jack's mum
    cared nor his dad, who I've only seen once, ransacking the kitchen hurriedly and left
    soon after. At least he left some food that he cooked, and Jack said we could eat it and so we did.
</p>

<p>
    Of course, the background image was a little misleading, well actually, very much so. A
    typical flat that you would find in Penang would look more like the ones below; one that 
    reflects a lot of the spirit of the people. Some would call it decrepit and poor but I beg to defer.
    To me, this was liberty. Something that I could never obtain in my suburban home with 
    at least 5 times the size a tiny flat where Jack used to live. But the space that it 
    gave me did not translate to freedom, because in my home, there were rules.
</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="/blog/img/flats_penang.jpg" alt="Demo Image">

<p>
    "This is only a roof." blurted Jack as we were in a random conversation that I could not 
    remember. "What do you mean?" I replied, confused. "I have lived here on this island for
    about 15 years but I never have a place that I could call home." "This is rented, it is not
    mine. Who knows when I have to move again?" with his voice increasingly emotional. I stayed quiet.
    I knew that this was not a conversation that I wanted to be involved in, nor did I understand what he 
    was saying. I always thought that I would trade places with him in a heartbeat if I had
    the chance to, and his complaints were merely a relic of his misunderstandings with
    his parents.
</p>

<p>
    Now that I am in search for a home, I have begun to wrap my head
    around what he felt. I don't think 
    that there is truly a way to understand since it has always been my choice to move. 
    I have a house in 
    Malaysia where my parents would welcome me back without a doubt. After all, an empty
    birdnest can be at times hollowing. 
</p>

<p>
    And in all honesty, this realization has slowly crept into me. It was cruel that a 15 year
    old should feel that way as I realize that to this day, I lack the maturity to comprehend
    nor grasp the idea of being homeless with a home. The feeling that my country has rejected me,
    that my country denies my existence hovers between the conscious and the unconscious; sometimes banishing me
    to a solemn torment, one that is only in my head, so they say. 
</p>

<p>
    Maybe our definitiion of belonging, of a home, is wrong. Maybe it should evolve over time.
    But the undeniable fact is that feeling belonged is perhaps an innate feature that we have 
    unlearned from the past in this modern world.
</p>]]></content><author><name>jhojy</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It was paradise. Everything was great; no rules, no requirements, nothing. Well, almost nothing. Jack's mum usually would be around, meandering around her house. I always wondered what she did but Jack would only scoff and said she was good for nothing. I would see her on her desk, and in the most sincerest form, acting busy whilst doing nothing. But I was young and carefree, and all I thought was "this is definitely better than my place".]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life as a Supporting Character</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/18/life-as-a-supporting-character.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life as a Supporting Character" /><published>2022-09-18T09:45:13-05:00</published><updated>2022-09-18T09:45:13-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/18/life-as-a-supporting-character</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2022/09/18/life-as-a-supporting-character.html"><![CDATA[<p>
    "You are the most useless gay friend ever!" sniggered Mariano as both of us stood 
    in the Railyard with beer in our hands. "Why don't you find a guy for me instead, be 
    useful for once." I retorted jokingly and he said "It does not work that way, haven't you 
    watched any tv shows before?"
</p>

<p>
    In the crowd of red, I couldn't really tell what was happening at all. Surrounded by
    the boisterous cheers because of an apparent touchdown and grunts from our opponents,
    Zayne told me that we were doing good and I trusted him. After all, I don't believe
    that I have even held a pigskin, if that is what it is called. All I could think then
    was that I paid $7 for less than a can of beer, and I am leaving behind work that I 
    know I would regret. But hey, it was game day and so, there we were. 
</p>

<p>
    Squinting my eyes, I still could not see anything. It wasn't bad eyesight that 
    plagued me, there was a guy infront of me that seemed to have a penchant to 
    block my view. Irritated, I turned to Mariano and told him that. He laughed and I 
    did too. There was nothing new to be the shortest guy around, I have gotten used to it.
    "Look at that girl with a cap behind you" Mariano signaled, nudging me subtly to her but 
    I turned around immediately which he responded kindly by hitting me on my shoulder.
</p>

<img class="img-fluid" src="/blog/img/plastic_cup.jpg" alt="Demo Image">

<p>
It is not difficult to feel out of place being a 5'6'' gay Malaysian (Zayne would say 5'4'' instead) in a tailgate party.
The tinge of envy I felt for the blonde was palpable, which bothered me further. 
Why did I care the attention that she had, of which she didn't even know exists? It was 
a confusing time, though it should not have been. But within the moments I started to
understand what it felt like to be a supporting character. Maybe the world is too small
for all of us to be the main character, or even our main character. 
</p>

<p>
    There is a bitterness with that thought, but after all, I was just another guy in red 
    within a sea of red, what is less 'supporting' than that? I couldn't just leave behind 
    the fact that I was one of the same, but different at the same time. But does it even 
    matter? Perhaps all I have to start doing is being accustomed to the life of a supporting
    character. And it is okay.
</p>]]></content><author><name>jhojy</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA["You are the most useless gay friend ever!" sniggered Mariano as both of us stood in the Railyard with beer in our hands. "Why don't you find a guy for me instead, be useful for once." I retorted jokingly and he said "It does not work that way, haven't you watched any tv shows before?"]]></summary></entry></feed>